So, tell me a little bit about your accident, John.
I was going on...
I was going on Eastbound in Washington, approaching a pedestrian walk.
But then...
And then what happened?
The person in front of me slammed their brakes and I didn't have enough space,
so I, fortunately, I rear-ended him.
That's basically a car, a car in fire.
We got out of the car.
We got transferred to the hospital.
But I was sighted.
You were sighted?
Yes.
Okay.
But your wife was in the car with you?
The wife.
Your wife, Jane?
Jane Doe here?
Jane was in the car with me.
Yes.
Okay. Sounds great.
Okay.
I get it.
So you stopped for a burning...
You stopped for a car and then you rear-ended that car
because it was stopped and your wife was in the car with you.
Is that how I got the facts?
Okay. Cool.
Well, thank you for filling out this form for me.
So let me go review it to make sure it's legible because, you know,
if a phone number digits off or something or I can't read something here,
I can't email you or call you, right?
Okay.
I totally understand how this happened.
So you were going Eastbound on Washington and you were at Owens or something, right?
Okay.
So you're at that intersection where the crosswalk is.
So I know exactly the cross streets and I know how the accident happened.
Got it.
Okay.
So I understand how the crash happened.
I know where you...
Where the intersection was.
Do you have any prior accidents or anything?
I have an accident.
Yes.
Was it a year ago, five years ago?
Three years ago?
Three years ago.
Okay.
Do you have any work comp claims?
No.
No work comp claims.
Okay.
I see on here you have some prior criminal history.
Like a robbery?
Okay.
Got it.
How many people were in your car?
Just my wife and you.
Just your wife and you.
And how many people were in the other car?
Three people.
What were the age of those people?
It was an adult and two minors.
Two minors?
How old were the minors?
I don't know.
16 and 10?
Yes.
16 and 10.
Okay.
There's five people in this accident.
Got it.
Okay.
And was it just a regular vehicle?
Well, I guess it doesn't matter.
You weren't driving for Uber or Lyft.
You were just driving your wife around.
Got it.
Okay.
I see that you got ticketed.
You got ticketed for failure following too closely.
And I see that police report.
TAR.
That traffic accident report there.
So, okay.
I'm going to make a copy of that stuff.
Okay.
I just want you to know that if you get a repair estimate before me,
I would like a copy of that repair estimate.
Okay.
You know, I don't want you to give me the repair estimate
from the insurance company because it's usually low.
So, if you get an estimate from your insurance company
or the defense insurance company,
which actually is you in this case.
So, if you get an estimate about your car from the insurance company,
it's usually too low.
So, I do want you to go get a third party estimate from somewhere else.
Got it?
Okay.
So, I'm guessing your vehicle is not drivable.
Isn't it in the ewing tow lot or something like that?
Yeah, it is in the ewing tow lot.
Okay.
So, it's probably going to be totaled because it did catch on fire.
If it's totaled, I'm going to need this DMV power of attorney filled out.
Okay.
We'll fill it out.
You just need a sign here.
And we'll notice it.
Okay.
So, let me get you to sign that.
Too bad, so sad.
Okay.
You still owe money on that car, right?
Yes, it was brand new.
Brand new.
Okay.
Did you get gap on that?
You did get gap.
Okay.
Well, we're going to need to know who the lean holder is.
So, I see that it's through Toyota Finance.
And I'm going to need those gap documents.
Okay.
So, that can help you with that gap.
If you, since the car is going to be total, I want you to go get the Kelly Blue book.
Okay.
To see how much the car is worth.
And then also any improvements that you made.
So, if you just tinted the windows recently or got a new engine or something,
make sure that you get me those receipts.
Okay.
Because then we can, after the insurance company gives me an estimate,
then I can try and negotiate and get more money because you just tinted your windows
and got a new engine on a brand new car.
Okay.
We're going to help you with that gap coverage, that gap claim,
as soon as we get those documents.
Basically, let's say that you bought that car 30 days ago,
and it's worth, you bought it for 35,000, but you drove it off the lot,
and it's worth 30,000 now.
So, you owe an extra 5,000 on it.
That gap coverage will pay for that difference.
Otherwise, you would have to pay for it because you got a bad deal at the, you know,
the place that you bought it from.
Okay.
Who's the owner of the vehicle?
Your wife is the owner of the vehicle.
Okay.
Cool.
Because you guys are both in the accident.
Got it.
I'm going to represent you guys.
Okay.
In name and shirt on the policies, your wife as well.
Your wife.
Okay.
Good.
So, as long as it's someone in the accident that we represent, then it's cool.
If not, then I would need something signed by the other person, your friend,
or whomever's car you're driving.
Okay.
So, where was this car tow to?
Was it the Ewing lot?
The Ewing lot.
Okay.
Cool.
So, we're going to need that car taken out.
Okay.
We're going to need it taken out of the tow yard because they're going to charge you every day that it's in there.
So, if it's in there for one day or five days, they charge you.
So, let's say they charge you $100 a day.
Okay.
Let's say it's in there for 10 days.
That's $1,000.
So, if they were going to give you $30,000 for that car, it starts taking money off of the car that they were going to give you.
So, let's say you had that car paid off.
And now, they've taken off $1,000.
They were going to give you $30,000, but now they're going to give you $29,000 because they've been taking off $100 a day.
Makes sense.
So, we need to get that out of there as soon as possible because we need to mitigate the damages.
Okay.
I have the battery on the line.
Can you want me to accomplish it?
Too late.
Okay.
So, anyway, you're only going to get $29,000 for it because you've left it in the tow yard for 10 days.
Just like you have a duty to mitigate damages.
Let's say your house was flooding and I was your landlord and you said, hey, Sandy, my house is flooding.
Can you fix my flooding?
You would have to stop the flooding.
You don't just let the water go.
You have a duty to mitigate.
So, you have a duty to go stop the flooding.
Maybe dry it out a little bit.
Not let it fill up until the whole house is full of water.
You have a duty to mitigate.
Okay.
So, here you have the same duty.
So, you have to make sure that you pull that car out of the tow lot.
And guess what?
If it stays in there too long, then they start selling your car and then you have no car.
Then you'll be really pissed off.
So, I did tell you about this.
Okay.
And by the way, you're going to have to authorize that tow.
I can't authorize it.
The owner has to authorize the tow.
So, your wife will have to authorize that tow.
Otherwise, everyone will just go out and take people's cars.
Okay.
So, because, you know, some people think that we're authorized to take that out.
You actually have to authorize us to take it out.
Okay.
And I'm going to need that VIN number because some of these tow lots.
They go by the VIN number.
Okay.
So, where do you want that vehicle tow to?
Is your house like an HWA community?
No, no.
Okay, perfect.
I wouldn't want it to be towed to HWA community and get retowed.
For you to be fine every day.
Okay, cool.
So, we'll just tow it to here.
Okay.
And you can put it in your garage or in the front yard or whatever.
I'm going to give you this text line.
You can't make phone calls to that text line because it'll go to nowhere because it's just a text line.
You can send your text messages there, though.
And we will respond in a few days as soon as we see it.
It's not like we're carrying our phones all day waiting for you to text us.
It's just something that's in our computer system.
So, when we're on your page or on your account,
we'll see that your text messages came through.
Okay.
So, if you need to call us, just call the phone number on the file here.
702-5910-11.
And then if you need to text us on the other line that I just gave you.
So, again, it's not immediate.
It might be a few days before we see it.
If you want something that's more urgent, call us.
Okay.
Like if you need your drug prescription refill or something, just call us because then we'll get it right away.
Can you make sure that you text me all of the pictures from the accident?
Sure.
And a selfie, too, because I'd like to know who I'm talking with.
Okay.
Cool.
We want a lifetime client, someone that refers as their friends and family.
So, we want to tell you what happens in an accident.
Normally, when you hire an attorney after the fact you're like,
Hey, I got a DUI.
Can you help me fix it?
Oh, I got audited on my taxes.
Oh, I got into a car accident.
It's not usually before.
You don't say, Hey, I think I'm going to get into a car accident today.
What kind of insurance coverage should I get, right?
So, normally, you know, I want you to tell you what happens because usually you come see me afterwards.
Next time, if you could do getting an accident, call me first.
The reason being is because I do not want you calling your insurance company.
So normally, it's not a good idea to talk to your insurance company or the defense insurance company.
Okay. It's just a really bad idea because they will index you.
They will put you in their computer system and say,
Oh, John has had two other accidents.
Since he had these two other accidents before, three years ago or five years ago or whatever,
we're going to blame all his injuries from before.
He just never got better from those last two accidents.
So if he's claiming back injuries and he's claiming back injuries this time,
we're going to just say it's from residual from those other two accidents.
So never, ever give them your information.
In fact, we redact all your information on the demand letter.
We take all your personal information out there.
We are trying to protect you so that you get a good offer.
They should not have to go look at these old accidents.
It's not fair.
You didn't cause the accident.
They should be based on this accident.
They were the ones that their client was negligent.
They hit you and you know, you should be compensated for your injuries and your pain and suffering.
Not, you know, taking a hit for two accidents that you had before.
Okay.
And the other thing is, I know maybe let's say you didn't have an accident.
Now you've put yourself into their database.
You called them.
They asked for your social.
They asked for your phone number.
They asked for your data birth.
You gave them your address.
You gave them everything.
And now they put you in their database.
And now they're going to put your injuries in there.
So let's say you've never had an accident before.
You're like, hey, cool.
I've never had an accident before.
That won't ever, that won't be detrimental to me at all.
You know, prejudicial or detrimental to me.
Okay.
Let's say you get into an accident five months from now.
This one might have been a fender bender.
But the next accident, you get hit by a Walmart.
A Walmart truck.
And that Walmart truck has a million dollars.
And now you're in the hospital and you have 300,000 dollar medical bills.
They're only going to give you half of an offer because you had this accident today.
Okay.
So we never ever want to give out indexing information to the insurance adjuster.
So always call us first so that we can protect you and call the insurance company on your behalf.
Okay.
The other thing is, we want to talk to the insurance company on your behalf
because we want to make sure that we tell them the whole story.
If you tell them the wrong set of facts, then they're going to think that you cause the accident.
That you merged in front of the defendant or whatever.
So we want to make sure that we, you know, get the story straight and everything
and give them the right set of facts so that they don't think that you're at fault for the accident.
The other reason that we want to talk to the insurance companies,
because you might not have all your injuries right away.
Maybe in a day or two, your shoulder starts hurting.
Maybe your neck starts hurting in a day or two.
You don't know.
You had all this, you know, epinephrine going through you.
You were all excited, adrenaline going through you at the date of the accident.
And now the next few days you're feeling hurt.
So let's say you forgot to tell them about that.
You told them about your back, but you didn't tell them about your neck or your shoulder.
Now they're going to say that that doesn't count because they have you on a recording today saying that only your back hurt.
But in a few days, your neck starts hurting, your shoulder starts hurting.
You didn't tell them all your injuries.
So we want to make sure that we protect you.
Okay, so we'd rather be the one that calls from now on.
So if you ever get an accident, give Van law firm a call first.
Okay.
So if your insurance company calls you from now on, tell them to call Van law firm.
If you've already talked to the insurance company, it's okay to talk to them about the property damage.
Just don't talk to them about your injuries or how the accident happened.
If they call you and ask you about the injuries or how the accident happened, tell them to call less.
But you can talk to them about the property damage if you've already talked to the insurance company.
Okay.
So getting your car fixed or totaled out, it may take 30 days or longer.
There is a state law that is a Nevada Administrative Code 686A.670.
The insurance company is 30 days to investigate.
Okay.
Nobody's going to be paying for your car unless they know that they did it.
I know in this case they know that you did it because you were cited.
You were the driver that hit the other car in front of you.
But normally it takes 30 days for them to review all the evidence, which means getting that police report that comes out in 10 or 15 days,
talking to all the witnesses, talking to all the parties, looking at all the pictures, looking at all the cars.
That's what they mean by duty to investigate, right?
Nobody's going to be paying for your car to get fixed or totaled or rental until they know that they're at fault.
So 30 days to look through all that evidence, witnesses, talking to the parties, police reports, looking at the pictures,
inspecting all those vehicles.
Okay.
So yeah.
Everyone thinks that if they get into an accident, they're going to automatically get their car fixed and a car rental.
It's not the case.
They have 30 days to investigate.
Okay.
So you said that your car's totaled probably in the tow yard.
Make sure to get the stuff out of the vehicle.
You know, things seem to disappear.
Tiffany, necklaces, and you know, cell phone chargers and things like that.
Just make sure you get all your personal effects out of there.
Okay.
If you want your car repaired sooner or totaled sooner, you're going to have to go through your insurance.
I see here that you have a $500 deductible.
You can pay that $500 deductible and then we will get it back later on if you didn't cause accident.
I know you're probably not going to get your deductible here because you caused accident.
But so long as if you didn't cause accident, you would get your $500 deductible back later on after they figured out who caused accident if it wasn't you.
And so long as there's enough insurance coverage for the property damage.
Okay.
So you would get your deductible back cad, you not cause accident.
If the other party has enough property damage insurance and that.
Okay.
Rental car.
Again, you're not going to get a rental for 30 days or more.
Sometimes it's less if they look at the police report and show that you didn't cause it.
Here, since you caused it, I'm glad that you have that coverage.
So you do have coverage for $50 a day.
I see on here.
And just make sure that you have a valid driver's license and a credit card.
And I'm assuming you're over 25, right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Because sometimes you have to be 25 to rent a vehicle.
And yeah, usually they need a credit card or like a bank-owned debit card.
So your Walmart credit card will not work.
Well, Walmart debit card will not work.
Don't buy anything extra.
So don't upgrade your car.
If you had a Kia, you have to get something similar to a Kia.
You can't go get yourself an escalate.
Okay.
And then don't buy extra insurance or things like that, you know, paying for that gas upgrade or whatever
because you won't get it back.
Okay.
So if you buy insurance or anything, you won't get it back.
If you didn't cause accident, I know you caused accident here, but if you didn't cause accident,
you would have, they'll, they'll pay you back for that rental.
Okay.
So we're going to be opening a claim with your insurance since you caused the accident.
We probably can't represent you because you caused accident.
Otherwise, everyone would be running into each other if they could get money for running into each other.
But we can represent your wife.
You know, your wife might as well make a claim because those three people that you hit, they'll probably make a claim.
Okay.
Your wife did have some damages.
She did go to the hospital here.
She might as well get paid back for her pain and suffering and all the inconvenience that she had.
Right.
Of having to rent a car and all that stuff.
Okay.
So let's get your wife with her claim open, you know.
She'll be making the claim against you, but it's not like we can erase this.
The insurance company is going to know that you caused an accident.
So she might as well make a claim.
Okay.
The other people are going to be making a claim.
Your wife might as well make a claim as well.
And anyway, she doesn't want her bills paid and all that stuff.
She wants us to deal with the gap.
The gap is going to be a real big issue to deal with because it's bridge crest.
And bridge crest takes a really long time to initiate gap.
Okay.
So you guys don't want to be the ones that are calling bridge crest like 15 times.
So we're going to open a third party claim against you.
So first party claim.
Our job is to make your case look the best and get you the most money in the shortest amount of time.
So, you know, she's your wife is injured and all that stuff.
The defendant's job is to make your case look bad like you're not injured.
Okay.
They're going to say that you're not injured.
So make sure that you treat regularly and soon.
So we need to get you into a doctor as soon as possible and you need to treat regularly.
You can't just go treating one week here, one week off, one month off.
It will really hurt your settlement.
Okay.
Yeah.
So make sure that you treat consistently with a chiropractor and a doctor.
They are different.
They're not the same.
Chiropractor is just like a band-aid.
You're trying that for a little bit to see if it works.
And if it doesn't work, you're going to continue on with the doctor.
The doctor is the one that has an MD at the end of his name.
He went to school a little bit longer.
He can prescribe medication.
You know what I mean?
The chiropractor is not really a real doctor.
He's just there's a band-aid just to see if you're, you know, getting better.
If you're not getting better, you continue on to the doctor at least once a month.
Okay. If you miss any appointments, make sure that you reschedule those as soon as possible, or it's going to affect your settlement.
Insurance company may not pay for it if you have significant gaps.
And it may affect your settlement if you have significant gaps in treatment.
And if you're not treating, then they're going to say any reasonable person that was injured would be treating.
So if you're not treating, it's going to affect your settlement.
Okay. Make sure that you tell the doctor about all your injuries, the first visit.
So if you have something, you forgot to tell them about your neck, and you tell them the second week later, it may not count.
Because you didn't tell them the first time that your neck was hurting.
So if you have to write it down, think about from your head to your toes, everything that's injured, injured, and say, write everything down so that you can tell the doctor on your very first visit.
Otherwise, it may not count if you say it later.
Okay.
Your pain scores, you are not a yo-yo.
You're not a nine, then a one, an eight, then a one.
Okay. Eight, then a two.
You're not a yo-yo.
You know what I mean?
If your pain scores may not always be the same, it may be like a scale.
Like maybe you're like a six to eight.
But just let the doctor know that if you're going to be like a yo-yo, the insurance company may not pay for that.
After you say that you're like a one or something, they'll be like, oh, he was all better.
That day, he was all better.
You know what I mean?
So just tell your doctor a range if you're not sure.
Just please don't fluctuate too much, okay?
So your settlement.
Your settlement is going to be based on what your medical bills are.
So if you have a dollar, I'm not going to be getting you a million dollars.
Just because you're hitting an accident.
If you have one dollar worth of medical bills, I'm not going to get you a million dollars.
And that does happen sometimes.
If I hit the rock, he's going to be like, you could hit me with a missile and I wouldn't be feeling any pain.
Even though he got hit in the car accident, he doesn't get any settlement because he didn't treat or anything like that.
If he's no medical bills.
It's going to be based on your medical bills.
What's in your medical records?
So whatever you told the doctor, if you tell your doctor every day that you have a paper cut,
I don't care if you went to the doctor every day for 365 days to tell them about your paper cut,
I can't get you a good settlement because you didn't tell the doctor about your injuries.
So it's going to be based on what's in your medical bills?
What's in your medical records?
The amount of insurance.
So let's say that there's $100,000 in here.
I'm going to need your bills to be somewhere between 40 to 60,000 to 40 to 60% of the 100,000 to get you that 100,000 because you probably want the maximum settlement.
So when you get to that point, we'll start tapering it down and we'll start gathering your medical bills and records to send in that demand.
So if there's not a lot of insurance, let's say it's a $25,000 policy, I'll have to stop this case early.
And sometimes some people are really injured.
I've had clients go to the doctors two to three times to the hospital two to three times because they're really injured.
But if there's not enough insurance, I can't make insurance just magically appear.
We can only go after how much insurance there is.
I can't go after the defendant most of the time because they usually don't have a pot to piss in or they'll follow bankruptcy by the time I get my judgment.
So unless that with person with Steve Win or something, probably not going after the defendant because they will hide assets, file bankruptcy, or they have no assets.
So I have to just go through the amount of insurance.
Reasonableness, it's pretty reasonable here that you have these injuries because it was a big impact.
Your car caught on fire and all that stuff.
If it was just a little bit of damage, it's not going to be as reasonable for me to say, like, hey, you know, you have all these injuries.
Okay.
The faster you get through the treatment that your doctor recommended, the faster we can get your case all settled out.
That does not mean treat faster than stop.
It means if your doctor recommends an MRI, you need to go to that MRI.
If the doctor recommends an injection, you need to go get that injection.
Because if I have to pull you to go get your MRI and if to pull you to get your injection, you're just delaying your case.
Okay.
I can lead you to water. I can't make you drink.
Make sure that you're not getting too many drug refills.
Okay.
Because they actually monitor that on the Nevada Prescription Drug Monitoring Program.
And then they're just going to say that you're just drug seeking.
Okay.
And then you'll probably get a low offer because they think that you just want to run up your bills to get drugs.
If you, since you went to the hospital, I need you to go get me those hospital bills and records.
Okay. Because those hospital bills and records, if I get them, it's going to take like 60 days.
If you get them, it's going to be 30 days.
I want you to show the hospital your insurance card because they need to bill health insurance.
The hospital is kind of sneaky.
Instead of getting paid 10 cents on a dollar by billing your health insurance, whether it's Medicare, Medicaid,
and a Blue Cross Blue Shield, they will just say, I never got his health insurance card so I never billed it.
And then they want to get the money from your settlement.
Okay. So each time you go in there, so when you go in there, in 30 days you go to your bills and records,
I need you to go present your health insurance.
Okay. So yeah, we need the bills and the records and then give us a copy.
And I just want them to bill your health insurance because once they know I'm involved, I have a duty to pay them.
So I will have to pay them the full amount.
So it's going to affect your settlement.
So more you help me cooperate on this, the better.
If the hospital doesn't bill your health insurance because you don't have health insurance or they just don't bill your health insurance,
they may send you to collections.
You need to enter into a payment plan with them for like $50 or $100 a month because otherwise you're going to have your credit affected.
And you know how you just got this brand new car or now you have this gap claim.
You need to also make payments on that.
Okay. Because if you don't then you're going to have bad credit and you won't be able to buy a new car.
Okay. The hospital doesn't have to accept an agreement from us to say we'll pay them later.
They will just send you to collections and it will affect your credit.
So enter into a payment plan with them unless you can pay them in full or pay them a settled amount.
Otherwise it's going to affect your credit.
Because you went to the hospital you went in an ambulance, right?
You're going to get more bills. You're going to get ambulance bills.
You're going to get the radiology bill for the X-rays and MRIs or CT scans that they did.
Probably CT scans or X-rays usually they don't do MRIs at hospitals.
But you're going to get a radiology bill and ambulance bill and emergency room physician bills.
So that physician that saw you he's contracted with the hospital.
Okay. So they're going to send you three additional bills including the hospital bills.
So just because you got one doesn't mean it stopped.
You're going to get a few more bills.
And you also have to enter into a payment plan with them or settle the debt or otherwise you're going to have bad credit.
Okay. So the police report it's going to take 10 to 15 days to get.
It says 10 days on there but you know it sometimes takes longer if there was a crime involved or if someone died.
Okay. And for me for us to get it since we're van law firm and we're not you we have to actually drop it off and then go back in three days to go pick it up.
So we call every day and see if it's ready.
When they tell us it's ready we drop off of sheet and then we go to the police station in three days to go pick up your police report.
If you need the police report faster because you want your car fixed or you want your car rental or whatever.
You need to go get it yourself. Okay. Got it.
So okay. And you know it's really important to get that police report because we need it to get liability accepted to see who caused accident and to get your car fixed or totaled out or your car rental.
Okay. We're doing a lot of things behind the scenes.
So you might not hear from us as much. Usually you'll hear from us a lot more in the beginning because it's been you know in the beginning there's a lot more.
We're trying to get your car fixed trying to get your rental or your car to allow your gap claim started or something.
But then after that we're doing things moderately until you're done treating you know.
So we're trying to get the police report for you. We're trying to help you with your getting your car fixed.
We're researching the policy limits. The defendant isn't need to tell me how much insurance there is.
Okay. I need to actually go higher private investigator to figure out how much insurance there is.
Okay. We're watching your treatment. So we know how much there is in policy limits.
We know if there's 25 grand or 100,000 your doctors don't know.
Okay. So they'll be calling our office all the time and saying hey can I go approve this MRI or hey can I prove this injection.
And we have to watch that to get it just right. It's like the three little bears.
Okay. You know how the porch is too cold and the porch is too hot.
We want to get it right in the middle medium like just warm in the middle.
It needs to be just right. Your medical bills need to be just right for me to get you that settlement.
Okay. So we're going to be watching your treatment. We're going to be approving your treatment when your doctors call us.
We may be helping you with wage loss claims.
You may not see everything that we're doing but we're doing a lot of things behind the scenes.
Your insurance company is not going to give you an offer until they see the demand letter.
We can't get them the demand letter until you're almost done treating.
So when you're 80% done treating we'll start requesting those bills and records.
Okay. But they're not going to the insurance company is not going to do it out of the graciousness of their heart.
You know and say hey here's an offer.
So no there will be no offers until I send off that demand letter.
And I'm not sending off that demand letter until you're almost done treating or done treating or have reached maximum medical improvement and plateaued.
Okay.
The insurance company wants to see the whole picture. I just can't send them 10 pages here and 10 pages there.
They will forget what they read last month because of 200 files sitting on their desk.
I do not want to give them half of your medical records because that creates a negative anchor.
They're going to give me a low offer and it's going to be hard to get me off that low offer because I showed them only half of your medical bills.
So there's no way for me to get you an offer quicker by sending in half of your stuff.
Okay. I want you to get the best offer. I want them to see as much as all of your medical records and bills or as much as humanly possible.
So that can get you the best offer.
How long will the case take?
Your case is not going to be like your mother's or sister's or best friend's or co-workers.
This is a different accident, different cars, different injuries, different insurance companies, different policy limits.
So it's not going to be the same.
You might have a policy limit of 25 grand which means it will be done quicker.
You may have a policy limit of 250,000 which means this case may take longer.
That's why these cases are not going to be the same as your co-workers case or whatever.
If your co-workers says, hey, my case was done sooner, it might have been a crappy case where there was very low limits.
Okay. It depends on how much insurance is available. It depends on the extent of your injuries.
If you are like, hey, I feel all better tomorrow, then this case will be done really quickly and you will get a low offer.
If you're still injured and you're treating for three months, your case might take a little bit longer.
If you're treating for a year, it may take a little bit longer.
So the case depends on the extent of your injuries, how much insurance is available, and also the policy limits.
It also depends on the other parties.
So remember how there's said that there's like five people involved.
You and your wife and the three people in the front? Well, you can never make a claim because you cause the accident.
Your wife can make a claim and these three other people in the front.
I got to wait for all four people to be done treating and to send in their demand.
The insurance company is not going to settle the case based on one person when there's three other people standing.
Okay. So if I'm really quick but those people hired ABC law firm and ABC law firm is taking their sweet time, that sometimes happens.
I can't get you an offer yet because those three people are still treating.
So it depends on when everyone puts their claim in.
Okay. If you want to come see us, please don't drop by.
Please just have an appointment.
We want to make sure that we review your case and we know everything is up to date and that we have a notary available, that we all didn't go to lunch.
So make an appointment and you can call us, text us, email us, and we'll set up an appointment for you.
So most of the time it's the claims assistance and case managers that are handling your case.
They are the front lines. They know what is happening on your case most of the time.
If you do need to speak to an attorney, we're all available here.
We have four attorneys. If you need to escalate something and talk to us, then definitely do call us.
But the attorneys are usually doing the heavier stuff.
Okay. You don't have your surgeon at the front getting your appointment or getting your copay, right?
You'd wonder what kind of doctor you're going to, right?
Same thing in a law office.
The attorneys aren't handling getting your police report and getting your medical records and filing stuff.
We're usually doing the heavier stuff.
We're doing the litigation. We're negotiating your case.
So when the adjuster says, hey, I want to give you a low ball offer, we're going to talk to them and say, no, you can't give our client a low ball offer because of this, this, and this.
So usually negotiating the case or filing a lawsuit.
So we do the heavier stuff, but we're always available.
There are four attorneys on staff. So if you need to make an appointment with an attorney, you definitely can.
Okay. There's going to be a lot of different people.
We have a very large team. So there might be different people calling you.
Okay. So it might be a victor that calls you when he's getting your car fixed and maybe someone else who's working on your demand letter.
It might be someone else during the treatment phase.
Okay. So we all work as a team.
There may be different people calling you.
It may not always be Susie, the case manager.
Okay. Okay.
Basically, let's go through the needs list here.
We put everything on here. So here's your homework.
Here's the stuff that I'm going to need.
I'm going to need that estimate that I told you about earlier.
I'm going to need those hospital bills and medical records and any medical bills that come in the mail.
And I'm going to need those gap documents that you're talking about.
Okay.
I'm sure that you get the stuff out of your car.
And remember how you had that accident from five years ago within the last three years.
I'm going to need those bills and records.
I need to know where you treated.
Or if you had a claim with another attorney, I'm going to need that file too.
Okay. I may not say that.
I may just say, hey.
I need to know where you treated.
Because if you go back to that law firm, then God forbid they say, hey, come back to us and do that again, right?
Do your accident with us.
Okay. We're going to need your insurance declaration page.
Can you pull it up right now on your phone?
Oh, okay. I got it. I see it right there.
Okay. So you're going to try and get that insurance declaration page pulled up at the intake.
Remember those receipts for that new engine and the tint that you have.
I'm going to need that as well.
Okay. And that is basically it for the intake portion.
Then I would like to go through the four flyers that we have in here.
The four flyers that we have in here.
So this our mission statement.
Our mission statement is to recover the most amount of money for you.
The highest settlement in the shortest amount of time.
And here's our core values.
Here is this.
If you think we're doing a good job, you know, the best thank you.
You can give us as a referral. Here's the things that we do.
We do auto accidents, motorcycle truck accidents, slip and falls, nursing home abuse and neglect,
dangerous products or drugs such as, you know, hernia, mesh or hips or talc,
Johnson and Johnson and things like that.
Jewel cigarettes. We do all that. Okay.
You can definitely give us a call or for your friend and family.
Here's the timeline of a personal injury case.
Normally you're treating. This could be three months to a year.
Sometimes it can be longer because there might be a lot.
A large insurance policy and you may be really injured.
You know, if there's a $250,000 policy or a million dollar policy,
you may be treating up to two years, three years.
I'm not sure.
Okay. But usually this phase here usually lasts three months to a year,
depending on how much insurance is available and how injured you are.
Then later on, we're doing the demand.
We're going to be gathering your medical records.
Your medical records take 60 days to come.
And when we request them, it takes 60 days.
We're reviewing them to see if we're having, if we have everything,
if we're missing anything.
And then we draft your demand letter.
Takes us about a month to draft, okay.
Then we send it off.
You know, we will have it reviewed a few times and that's stuff.
That's why this phase takes so while.
Then we'll send it off and the gesture is 30 days to review it.
And then he's negotiating back and forth for the next 30 days or three months or so.
He'll ask us for anything that's missing.
He'll give us an offer.
We'll be negotiating.
But he needs at least 30 days to review that demand letter.
Then it's either going to settlement phase.
You like the offer.
And we're asking for doctors for reductions or talking to your insurance,
health insurance company for the subrogation lien.
And that might take a while.
Just because we get your check doesn't mean magically you'll have a check tomorrow.
We're still working on trying to get you a better settlement, okay.
So that might take one to four months.
Or you don't like it the offer.
And we're going to go to file a lawsuit against them.
And that might take a year to three years.
Okay.
There's a lot more to do.
We need to go to court.
We need to do deposition.
So that's basically the timeline of the case.
Okay.
So here.
If my...
If Susie the case manager is not paying attention to you and she's not returning your calls,
make sure you call my own personal assistant Vanessa.
Okay.
She's our client satisfaction manager.
You can definitely give her a call.
We want to make sure that client satisfaction and customer care
and client communication is happening.
So if no one's talking to you and you need someone higher up,
you can call her.
She will reach out to me and let me know what's going on.
Okay.
So here's her number.
So let's go through these forms.
Here is all the stuff that you need to get me.
So this is your homework.
Here's your text line.
Make sure you only text that message.
You know, and you can text me messages or you can text me photos.
Do not call that number because it will go to nowhere.
And you'll think that we never pick up our phones.
If you need to call us, call this phone number.
Here's your email, case email address,
and here's your case manager's email.
So it's Susie.
So it's Susie at Van law firm is your case manager.
And here's your email,
johndoatfilevine.com or something.
Okay.
Cool.
Here's the doctors that you're going to.
We're going to send you to this doctor.
Because which one's by your house?
Okay. Let's look at this map.
Oh, you live right here in this zip code 8901.
Well, this doctor is probably closest to you and this chiropractor.
So we'll send you to these two people.
Okay.
Because we did look on a map.
And we did see that you live in 8901.
So we found the closest doctors for you.
Because if you do go to litigation,
I didn't refer you to someone.
I showed you a map and you found the closest person to you.
Okay.
Cool.
Let's go through the rest of this.
So here we have a high tech letter.
This is so that we can get you your medical bills and records.
Okay.
For cheaper.
Here is internet and surveillance.
It's very important that you do not do anything bad during your case.
It's going to hurt your case.
If you have a very large case that's a $250,000 or more,
they may hire a private investigator to follow you around for a week.
They'll spend $1,000 to have some guy tell you for a week to save themselves $50,000.
Okay.
We don't want you picking up heavy bags of concrete.
Lifting things.
Okay.
When you're saying your back hurts or your neck hurts.
So don't be posting things on Instagram or Facebook of you riding horses and climbing mountains.
You can go post that after you get your settlement.
But until then, just be very careful.
You know, if you have to lift something, ask your friend to lift it or whatever.
I understand if that is your job, then we'll figure a way around it.
But try to.
Get light duty or something.
Okay.
Consent for disclosure for information.
So that is so that we can disclose information to your medical providers,
your lean companies, any loan companies that you get a loan from,
medical billing record companies, things like that.
So we can talk to them.
HIPAA.
So this is so that we can get your medical records.
Okay.
Here on the yellow line, you can just sign here on all these documents on the yellow line.
They're yellow for a reason.
Okay.
Here is a limited power of attorney.
That limited power of attorney is so that we can get your check.
Your check is going to come in your name and my name,
rather than having you come down just to sign a check so I can deposit it.
I can sign your name on your behalf and deposit into our trust account
so that we can get the money paid to you and your doctors and us and everything.
Okay.
Here's a general power of attorney.
So a general release is for us to get your police report usually.
Okay.
And then the other thing here is a Medicare form.
Just need you to sign here.
Okay.
Because we're not going to fill out any information on here
because we're not going to give out indexing information.
So we just need to sign on the yellow line.
Okay.
Next thing here is a lean.
This basically states that we are owed 33 and a third of what we recover
and then 40% if we go to trial.
Okay.
And then we'll discuss your property damage.
I am not a magician.
You only have liability insurance so I can't get your car fixed.
Okay.
Or hey, you do have collisions.
So we're going to try and help you get your car fixed.
Just need your initial and one of these two lines.
You do have rental coverage.
So we can go do that.
The police report may take 10 days or longer.
Because again, it fits us.
It takes 10 days or longer.
Because we have to go drop it off there.
If you want to get it faster, you can go obtain it yourself.
Remember you have a duty to mitigate.
You need to get your car out of there otherwise you're going to incur
impound fees or your vehicle may be sold at auction.
You do understand you do need a driver's license to rent a car
and a credit card or a major debit card.
Okay.
And you do understand that property damage may take 30 days or longer, right?
Okay. Cool.
Just need your initial here and then sign your name.
Thank you.
So you have to have confidence because you have to make sure
that the client retains us.
They don't want someone that doesn't is unsure what they're doing
that lacks confidence to hire them.
Okay.
You need to make sure that this is completely filled out
because what you put in is what you get out.
So if you don't have things filled in, the person may die
and then we don't know who their emergency contact is
and we don't know how to open a probate
because we don't have their emergency contact.
Okay.
We may not know how the accident happened
because you put the fax in wrong
or if you didn't review everything to see if it's legible,
we won't have anyone to contact or an email address
or a phone number to work.
So make sure that you have everything filled out.
Okay.
Yeah, because otherwise it does affect us later
and you lose credibility.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't write anything down here.
Can you tell me how the accident happened again?
That's not good.
You want everything upfront.
And also you're explaining to them the process
so that they know what to expect
so they don't mess up their case.
Okay.
They don't have gaps in treatment
because you didn't tell them.
You didn't tell them how long the process takes
so they think that they're going to get an offer
in six months.
You're going to have a way better settlement offer
a higher valued case if you told them everything
from the beginning.
So do not rush through it.
Okay.
Make sure that you're thorough.
There's a reason I put this checklist together.
No other firm really has this checklist
unless they stole it from us.
Okay.
I spent a lot of time
I'm still editing it to this day
and adding things in there.
So yeah.
Just make sure you go through everything.
It's there for a reason.
Make sure everything's filled out
because what if you get hit by a bus?
And now we don't have you there
and I'm wondering what happened in the case.
And now I need to call a client and say,
hey, I'm reviewing this case
and I don't know what happened
because nothing was filled in.
I lose credibility.
The client's wondering now,
did I hire the right attorneys
and now I should watch them more
and you're going to be micromanaged a little bit more
because you've lost credibility.
So once you lose credibility,
they're going to be like,
I wonder if I hired the right attorney.
I better double check all of this shit.
Okay.
So that's important.
If you think that the client isn't willing to treat,
we're personal injury attorneys.
Okay.
That's why you see all these billboards
with personal injury.
You don't see property damage attorneys.
If they're not willing to treat,
you think that they're any bit wavering on that.
Either have us talk to them.
You know, have an attorney talk to them
and explain to them.
If you don't treat,
I've seen,
if you don't hire an attorney and if you don't treat,
so if you don't hire an attorney
because no one does property damage,
we are only personal injury attorneys
so you can only hire us if you're injured.
I've seen them,
your clients get screwed over.
Then insurance companies like,
I don't know, I don't cause it.
I'm not fixing your car.
Okay.
And then you're having to deal with that
and fight with insurance company.
And no one's going to want to help you
because you never open a claim.
Okay.
But also, if they're just going to be,
no, I'm not treating.
I don't want to open a claim.
The goal is not to sign every case.
It's to sign the cases that we can win.
It brings down our average.
It makes our staff work harder
because now we're going to the case
that we have to like,
convince someone to do something.
And I need a certain amount of money
per case to break even.
Just like if you were to sell blow dryers.
If you've cost you $25 to sell that,
to make that blow dryer,
you can't go selling them for $20,
otherwise you're going to go bankrupt.
In this firm,
it's probably $68,000 per case to break even.
So if someone's not willing to treat or anything,
just don't even take the case.
Okay. It's not quantity.
It's quality.
Okay.
And if you're not sure,
make sure that you speak to one of us
before that happens.
So we can talk to the client
because it may be something different.
It may be us explaining it to them.
We may be able to explain it better.